CHARLIE BROOKE O'HARA

charlie.b.ohara@gmail.com charliebohara.com github.com/cbohara linkedin.com/in/cbohara

TECHNICAL SKILLS

AWS
GLUE
LAMBDA
KINESIS
SQS
GLUE
ATHENA
REDSHIFT
DYNAMODB

PYTHON PYTEST

SQL

SPARK HADOOP

LINUX CLI BASH SCRIPTING

GIT

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

AWS Certified - Data Analytics Speciality, Solutions Architect Associate. Senior Data Engineer experienced with building real-time and batch data pipelines with AWS serverless infrastructure and writing Python and Bash scripts for automation. Self-starter who is quick to learn new technologies and capable of building applications with little guidance. Loves to share knowledge and author of technical blog posts with over 40K total views. Always ready to jump in and help the team, and consistently provide excellent service to stakeholders.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Engineer - Life360

San Diego, CA/Remote - May 2019 - present

- Lay the groundwork with a newly established team responsible for ingesting terabytes of data and billions of events per day into a fresh data lake while managing a data warehouse containing pedabytes of data
- Develop and maintain real-time streaming pipelines that deliver data to third party partners within 30 seconds, which generates 15% of company revenue
- Work with a team of engineers and analysts to consolidate our events system infrastructure to leverage AWS native services
- Build data pipelines to flow events from external partners into the data lake to provide rich data sets for our analysts
- Educate and empower coworkers to take advantage of our new data ecosystem

Data Software Engineer - Verve

San Diego, CA/Remote - July 2017 - May 2019

- Built an automated data pipeline to ingest third-party audience data from multiple partners to better understand our users
- Wrote Bash scripts to launch ad-hoc Hadoop Streaming, Apache Pig, and Snowflake jobs to automate operational processes in order to streamline delivery
- Worked with a team to establish a workflow for building, distributing, and ultimately
 executing against Python and Java code artifacts within our ecosystem
- Actively involved in the interviewing, training, and mentoring of a junior engineer

Big Data Engineer - Algebraix Data

San Diego, CA — February 2017 - July 2017

- Built and ran Spark SQL and PySpark applications in an AWS EMR cluster to test proprietary query acceleration algorithm against TPC-H and TPC-DS benchmarks
- Wrote Bash scripts to facilitate product installation on variety of operating systems
- Wrote Python scripts for general automation and log analysis

Quality Assurance Engineer - Grizzly

San Diego, CA — September 2016 - February 2017

- Setup and built client WordPress applications leveraging Docker
- Wrote PHPUnit tests that were integrated with a continuous integration tool
- Wrote Python scripts for data mining, cleaning, analysis, and transfer

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Barbara - Bachelor's - Biology